<string-array name="Description">
        <item>Android is an operating system for mobile devices such as smartphones and tablet computers. Android Operating System is built on the open Linux Kernel.
It includes a touch screen user interface, widgets, camera, network data monitoring and all the other features that enable a cell phone to be called a smartphone.
Android is a platform that supports various applications, available through the Android Play Store.
The Android platform also allows end users to develop, install and use their own applications on top of the Android framework.
The Android framework is licensed under the Apache License, with Android application developers holding the right to distribute their applications under their customized license.
The Android platform is the product of the Open Handset Alliance, a group of organizations collaborating to build a better mobile phone.
The group, led by Google, includes mobile operators, device handset manufacturers, component manufacturers, software solution and platform providers, and marketing companies.
From a software development standpoint, Android sits smack in the middle of the open source world.</item>

        <item> It was originally founded and developed by Andy Rubin, Rich Miner,Chris White, and Nick Sears under the name "Android Inc",in October,2003.
  Google acquired Android Inc in July,2005.
  On 5 November 2007, Google formed Open Handset Alliance(OHA).
Open Handset Alliance :-
       It is a group of 84 technology and mobile companies who have come together to accelerate innovation in mobile and offer consumers a richer, less expensive, and better mobile experience.It includes Google, HTC, Sony, Dell, Intel, Motorola, Qualcomm, Texas Instruments, Samsung Electronics, T-Mobile, Sprint Corporation, Nvidia etc.
       OHA members are primarily mobile operators, handset manufacturers, software development firms, semiconductor companies and commercialization companies.
The first android phone was launched by HTC on 22nd October,2008.HTC Dream (also known as T-Mobile G1)was the first commercially launched device to be powered by Android operating system.

History of Android versions :-
    Android 1.0 (2008)
    Android 1.5 Cupcake (2009)
    Android 1.6 Donut (2009)
    Android 2.0 Eclair (2009)
    Android 2.2 Froyo (2010)
    Android 2.3 Gingerbread (2010)
    Android 3.0 Honeycomb (2011)
    Android 4.0 Ice Cream Sandwich (2011)
    Android 4.1 Jelly Bean (2012)
    Android 4.4 KitKat (2013)
    Android 5.0 Lollipop (2014)
    Android 6.0 Marshmallow (2015)
    The latest version of the platform is now Nougat Android 7.1.1.</item>

        <item>INSTALLATION PROCESS

website - https://developer.android.com/studio/index.html

WINDOWS -  .
-> download and launch the .exe fileyou downloaded.
-> follow the setup wizard to install android studio and necessary tools.

Ubuntu - download the .zip file and unpack to any appropriate location.
-> To launch android studio , open a terminal , navigate to the android-studio/bin/directory , and type ./studio.sh command
->select wheather you want to import previous android studio or not then click OK
-> the android studio wizard guides you further includes downloading Android SDK that required for developement

REQUIRED LIBRARIES FOR 64-bit machines
sudo apt-get install libc6:i386 libncurses5:i386 libstdc++6:i386 lib32z1 libbz2-1.0:i386
(if you are using 64 bit version of ubuntu and you need to install 32bit libraries )

MAC
-> launch the android studio DMG file.
-> drag and drop android studio into the appliction folder then launch the Android studio
-> select wheather you want to impot previous android studio setting  then click OK</item>

        <item>Additonal Components: There are some additonal components which are used to build
entities(like:Activities,Broadcast Receivers,Content Provider).
List of additional components are:

1>Manifest:It is the file in which it contains complete information about the application.
2>Resources:it is used to provide external elements(like:colors,animation,bitmaps etc.).
3>Intents:It is used to access other component(Activities) of same Application.
4>Layout:It is the hierarchies(UI) of application .
5>Views:It is the Class that contain components(viewgroup) such as button,textview,edittext,etc.
6>Fragments:It is used to build Dynamic User Interface and it should be used within activity.It is kind of sub-activity. </item>

        <item>->Broadcast Receivers simply respond to broadcast messages from other applications or from the system itself.
->These messages are sometime called events or intents. For example, applications can register for the ACTION_BOOT_COMPLETED system event which is fired once the Android system has completed the boot process.

To set up a Broadcast Receiver in our android application we need to do the following two things-
1)Creating the Broadcast Receiver.
2)Registering Broadcast Receiver.
There is one additional steps in case you are going to implement your custom intents then you will have to create and broadcast those intents.

</item>
        <item>An activity is an application component .  Activity represents a single screen . All activities interact with the user , Such as dial the phone , take a photo , send an email or view a map . Activity class take care of creating a window for you in which you can place you UI with setContentView(view) . If an application has more than one activity , then one of them should be marked as the activity that is presented when the application is launched . For example , an email application might have one activity that shows a list of new emails , another activity to compose an email , and another activity for reading emails .
</item>

        <item>

The Lifecycle of an Activity comprises a collection of methods.
These methods are: OnCreate(), OnStart(), OnResume(), OnPause(), OnStop(), OnDestroy(), OnRestart().

 OnCreate() : OnCreate() method is used for initializing the class as well as providing the view.
 OnStart() : OnStart() method will start the application.
 OnResume() : OnResume() method will create interaction with activity.
 OnPause() : OnPause() method will partially hide the activity.
 OnStop() : OnStop() method will completely hide the activity.
 OnDestroy() : OnDestroy() method will destroy the application.
 OnRestart() : OnRestart() method will called after your activity has been stopped, prior to it being started again.


</item>
        <item>
            *******SHORT DESCRIPTION-
A layout defines the visual structure for a user interface, such as the UI for an activity or app widget.
	For example- The activity_main.xml is a layout file available in res/layout directory,that is referenced by your application when building its interface.


*******LONG DESCRIPTION-
	An Android layout is a class that handles arranging the way its children appear on the screen.
 	Anything that is a View (or inherits from View) can be a child of a layout. All of the layouts inherit from ViewGroup (which inherits from View) so you can nest layouts.
	 You could also create your own custom layout by making a class that inherits from ViewGroup.

-->There are different types of Layouts available----
1)LINEAR LAYOUT-It is a basic layout that arrange the different components either in vertical form or in horizontal form.
2)RELATIVE LAYOUT-It is also a basic layout which arrange the views w.r.t. its parent or its neighbours.
3)TABLE LAYOUT-It is a view that groups views into rows and columns.
4)ABSOLUTE LAYOUT-It enables you to specify the exact location of its children.
5)FRAME LAYOUT-FrameLayout represents a simple layout for the user interface of Android applications.
6)LIST VIEW-It is a viewgroup that displays a list of scrollable items.
7)GRID VIEW-GridView let you arranges components in a two-dimensional scrolling grid.

        </item>


        <item>**********Short discription:
It align all its components in either horizontal or vertical position.


**********Long Discription:
*In Android, LinearLayout is a common layout that arranges 'components' in vertical or horizontal order, via orientation attribute.
*In additional, the highest “weight” component will fill up the remaining space in LinearLayout.

</item>

        <item>Short discription:
It specify that how components of realtive layout are views are positioned relative to each other.
components can be positioned by using their neighbouring components or parent .
List of attributes:

android:layout_above
android:layout_alignBottom
android:layout_alignLeft
android:layout_alignParentBottom
android:layout_alignParentEnd
android:layout_alignParentLeft
android:layout_alignParentRight
android:layout_alignParentStart
android:layout_alignParentTop
android:layout_alignRight
android:layout_alignStart
android:layout_alignTop
android:layout_below
android:layout_centerHorizontal
android:layout_centerInParent
android:layout_centerVertical
android:layout_toEndOf
android:layout_toLeftOf
android:layout_toRightOf
android:layout_toStartOf
        </item>

        <item>TableLayout is used to be arranged groups of views into rows and columns. You will use the &lt;TableRow&gt; element to build a row in the table. Each row has zero or more cells; each cell can hold one View object.

Attributes:
1.android:collapseColumns
            It collapse the columns(meet more then two columns). The column indices must be separated by a comma: 1, 2, 5.


2.android:shrinkColumns
            The zero-based index of the columns to shrink(reduce size of columns). The column indices must be separated by a comma: 1, 2, 5.


3.android:stretchColumns
            The zero-based index of the columns to stretch(increase size of columns).  The column indices must be separated by a comma: 1, 2, 5.
</item>

        <item>Grid Layout is a layout which arrange the components(views) in the tabular form.It is similar to TableLayout ,but here we can define no. of rows and columns by the attributes (rowCount and columnCount).Grid layout is mainly used to align its child views in cells which are the horizontal and vertical intercepts of an invisible line. Each view child is place in a cell and the cells are numbered with the horizontal and vertical indexes.
</item>

        <item>
            FrameLayout arranges the components in the form of stack,with the most recently added child on top. They are designed to block an area on the screen.Elements that overlap will be displayed overlapping.
we can use android:visibility attribute in XML or setVisibility method in java for hiding(GONE) ,for displaying (VISIBLE) any elements.
        </item>

        <item>
            Using ConstraintLayout we are able to create large and complex layouts with flat hierarchy.It does not support nesting of ViewGroups.It is similar to RelativeLayout ,but it is more flexible than RelativeLayout.we can build our layout with ConstraintLayout entirely by drag-and-dropping instead of editing the XML.
        </item>

        <item>
            Long Description:
Every components that you have dovelop for your application, must be declare in the manifest file called AndroidManifest.xml which is root of your project.If you do not declare it in a manifest file,then component will not considerd by the operating system.
1.Versioning:&lt;manifest&gt; tag consists of application versioning information (android:versionCode and android:versionName) helps the android systems to maintain the upgrade/ downgrade of application.
2.Activity:Android application consists of four types of components:

*Service
*Content providers
*Broadcast receivers
*Activity
3.Permission:Android OS model requires applications to highlight what features of OS or resources they are going to use(such as bluetoth,Wifi,camera,sensors,etc).
4.SDK Version:
*manifest file provides the information to the system while installation
*checking for the availability of SDK version and install accordingly.

        </item>

        <item>
            Event handling:-
	It is the mechanism that control the event and decide what should happen if  event accur  this mechanism have the code which is know as event handling that is executed when an event accur.
There are 3 concepts related to Android Management:-
1.Event Listeners
2.Event Listeners Registration
3.Event Handlers
Event Listeners  Using An Onclick in XML Attribute and setOnclickListener in JAVA:-
	 Onclick =Using the android:onclick XML attribute Where you just use the name of a public method with the signature Void name (View v) .

	In main activity we call a button through (fun )method  out side the onCreate method .

public class MyActivity extends Activity {
protected void onCreate(Bundle savedInstanceState) {
super.onCreate(savedInstanceState);
setContentView(R.layout.sample_main);
}

public void fun(View v) {
//Add some logic
}
}
setOnclickListener  interface :-
	when your Activity class implements the Listener interface and you put the handler method in the main Activity and then you call setonclicklistener(this).
	when Using the setOnclickListener method Where you pass an object that implement the onclickListener interface .
	To specify an action when the button is pressed, set a click listener on the button object in the corresponding activity code

public class MyActivity extends Activity {
protected void onCreate(Bundle savedInstanceState) {
super.onCreate(savedInstanceState);
setContentView(R.layout.content_layout_id);

final Button button = findViewById(R.id.button_id);
button.setOnClickListener(new View.OnClickListener() {
  @Override
    public void onClick(View v) {
        myFancyMethod(v);
    }
});
}
}

</item>

        <item>
            The screenOrientation is the attribute of activity element. The orientation of android activity can be portrait, landscape, sensor, unspecified etc.
    You need to define it in the AndroidManifest.xml file.
            

   The common values for screenOrientation attribute are as follows:

   unspecified -	It is the default value. In such case, system chooses the orientation.
   portrait    -	taller not wider
   landscape   -	wider not taller
   sensor	    -	orientation is determined by the device orientation sensor.

</item>
        <item>
        *****SHORT DISCRIPTION- -
        A string resource provides text strings for your application with optional text styling and formatting . There are three types of resources that can provide your application with strings-
        1)STRING -
        2)STRING ARRAY -
        3)QUANTITY STRINGS(PLURALS) -
        *****LONG DISCRIPTION--
        By default  over android project includes a string resource file at "edit _message" and set the value to "Enter a message."
        The string class reprents a character string . Whwn a string is created , At that time the value of string is not changed .
        For example --
        String str="abc" .
        Types of resources--
        1)String - A single string that can be referenced from the application or from other resource files (such as an XML layout) . A string is a simple resource that is referenced using the value provided in the name attribute .
        CODE--
       
    </item>

        <item>
Image files like .png , .jpg , .gif or XML that are complied into bitmaps,state lists,shapes,animation drawables.They are saved in res/drawable/ and accessed from R.drawable class.

*******LONG DESCRIPTION :-
There are different types of drawables :-
1. Bitmap File :-
A bitmap graphic file (.png, .jpg, or .gif). Creates a BitmapDrawable.
file location : res/drawable/file_name.jpg (.png,.jpg, or .gif)
Resource reference :
In XML : @drawable/file_name
In Java: R.drawable.file_name
2.Nine-Patch file :-
Nine-Patch file is a stretchable bitmap file that Android will automatically scale to accomodate the size of the view.file extension : .9, like file.9.png and defined in XML format using &lt; nine-patch &gt; tag.
    3. Shape drawable :-
    supports all basic shapes such as -line, oval and rectangle and defined in XML format using &lt;string-array&gt; tag.
        4.State lists :-
        is a group of several images that are mapped to different states of an object.Android uses the correct image form list based on current state of object and defined in XML format using &lt; item &gt; tag.
            5. Layer List :-
            A Drawable that manages an array of other Drawables.

            Adding an image to res/drawable folder :-
            1.Right click on res, new Image Asset
            2.On Asset type choose Action Bar and Tab Icons
            3.Choose the image path
            4.Give image name in Resource name
            5.Next->Finish
        </item>

        <item>
            *******SHORT DESCRIPTION:
            XML files that contain simple values are stored in the value directory

            *******LONG DESCRIPTION:
            XML files that contain simple values, such as strings, integers, and colors are always maintained separately in sub-directory values/ under res/ directory of the project.
            When you create a resource in any sub directory under res/ you can use it by referencing its resource ID. All resource IDs are defined in your project's R class.

            *  Here are some filename conventions for resources you can create in this directory −

            1)  arrays.xml  -  for resource arrays, and accessed from the R.array class.
       
            2)  integers.xml - for resource integers, and accessed from the R.integer class.
       
            3)  bools.xml   -  for resource boolean, and accessed from the R.bool class.
       
            4)  colors.xml -   for color values, and accessed from the R.color class.
       
            5)  dimens.xml  -  for dimension values, and accessed from the R.dimen class.
       
            6)  strings.xml  - for string values, and accessed from the R.string class.
       
            7)  styles.xml  -  for styles, and accessed from the R.style class.

            *  There are two ways you can access a resource:

            In .java file :  [ &lt;package_name&gt;.]R.&lt;resource_type&gt;.&lt;resource_name&gt;
            &lt;package_name&gt;  :  Name of the package in which the resource is located (not required when referencing resources from your own package).
            &lt;resource_type&gt; :  R subclass for the resource type.
            &lt;resource_name&gt; :  Resource filename without the extension.



            In XML file :  @[&lt;package_name&gt;:]&lt;resource_type&gt;/&lt;resource_name&gt;

            &lt;package_name&gt;  :  Name of the package in which the resource is located (not required when referencing resources from the same package)
            &lt;resource_type&gt; :  R subclass for the resource type
            &lt;resource_name&gt; :  Resource filename without the extension.
        </item>


        <item>


            ->A View is an object that draws something on the screen that the user can interact with.
            It is responsible for measuring , layouting and drawings themselves and their child elements.
            ->There are number of Views (UI controls)provided by Android that allow us to build the graphical user interface for our app.
            ******Some are:--
            1)TextView:-   TextView displays text to the user and allows them to edit programatically.
            2)EditText:- This is a predefined subclass of TextView that permits rich editing capabilities.
            3)Button:- Button represents a push button. A Push Button can be clicked or pressed by the user to perform an action.
            There are different types of buttons used in android such as ImageButton, toggleButton, radiobutton.
            4)CheckBox:- An on or off switch that can be toggled by the user and can be used to select multiple options from a group of selectable options.
        </item>


        <item>

            ViewGroup is an object which is responsible for arranging the components(View) in different manner.

            It is a base class of some special UI class that can contain other view objects as children.

            Android contains the following commonly used Viewgroup subclasses:-
            1)LinearLayout:- Arrange components in Linear Form.
            2)Relative Layout:- Arrange the views w.r.t to its parent or its neighbours.
            3)Table Layout:- Arrange the views in tabular form.
            4)Grid Layout:- It is similar to table layout but here we can define number of rows
            and number of columns by the Attribute rowcount and columnCount.
        </item>


        <item>

            TOAST-
            Toast can be used to display information for the short period of time . Toast is a subclass of java.lang.objectclass.
            TOAST CLASS-
            Toast class is used to broadcast any massage on any specific event .
            It uses a static method makeText which takes three parameter(context,massage,duration).
            NOTE-context class is a abstract class which is used to convey the massage in different classes and toast class is independent upon activity.
            ****Toast consist two constants-
            LENGTH_SHORT-Display view for short time.
            LENGTH_LONG-Display view for a long duration.
            Method of a toast class is--
            Public static Toast Make Text(Context cntext,chr seqence text,int duration)
            --It having text and duration .
            public void show()
            --Display the toast.
            public void set margin(float.horizontalMargin,float.verticalMargin)
            --It changes the vertical and horizontal Margin difference.


        </item>


        <item>

            Layoutinflater is used to manipulate android screen using predefined XML layouts . This class is used to instantiate layout XML file into its corresponding view objects . It is never used directly .

        </item>
    </string-array>